Dive deep into serious learning,
and get excited!
Witness a miracle born from fossils.
Once upon a time, in a certain place...
Prehistoric creatures full of personality!
Tirano, Stego, Ammonite,Trilobite.
They've been saying "hi" for 500 million years.
Prehistory! Everybody Say (Roar!)
Ancient, Alright! Future, FLY High!
A herd of mammoths! Run!
Thud thud thud thud! On your marks, get set, go!
Dive deep into serious learning,
and get excited!
Witness a miracle born from fossils.
Dive deep into serious learning,
Playing for real.
The universe begins with passion.
Super happy!
Eh?
Why is a warp zone open?!
Serious Mata-Kamen's Trial
It wasn't me!
It wasn't me either!
Welcome to the world of serious prehistoric creatures!
Welcome!
To the Serious Prehistoric Creature Test
to test your knowledge!
My name is...
Mata-Kamen!
What a sense of naming...
I mean...
WHAT IS THIS!?
It's a prehistoric creature knowledge test!
If you don't pass, everyone falls in!
everyone falls in!
Huh?
What are you saying?!
First question!
Name the dinosaur named by paleontologist Henry Osborn
What is the name of this dinosaur?
What is this?!
If you run at the displayed speed,
you get the right to answer!
Now, what's the answer?
Eh?
Am I answering?
That's right!
Wait, what was the question?
The correct answer is Tyrannosaurus!
Kanna-kun!
That was from Episode 1!
Tetori!
If you get the next one wrong,
the slide goes vertical!
What's with this death game?!
Now, next question!
Name the characteristic head feature possessed by ceratopsians such as Triceratops
What is this part of the Triceratops called?
I-It's faster than before!
This is suddenly impossible!
No, it's not impossible!
Remember all our club activities!
You can solve this!
Tetori...
Frill!
It's a frill!
Now that you're getting into the groove...
...next question!
Answer in two Kanji characters the word that Matajiro Yokoyama translated into Japanese and popularized
What term did Matajiro Yokoyama translate into Japanese?
Huh?
Who's that?
How sad, considering he was always with you in the clubroom!
It's Matajiro Yokoyama!
Matajiro!!!
He's the Father of Paleontology,
who translated "dinosaur" as *Kyōryū*
and spread it across Japan!
Sorry for not answering correctly earlier!
Following previous examples where extinct reptiles were translated into Japanese as 'Ichthyosaur' (Gyoryū) or 'Plesiosaur' (Kubinagaryū),
Matajiro Yokoyama was the first in Japan to translate 'Dinosaur' as 'Kyōryū' (meaning 'fearful lizard')
Tetori actually answered it!
Wait, why is a person like that doing this?!
Watching you guys...
...made me want to test your strength!
Matajiro-sensei was watching our activities?!
What an absolute honor!
He passed out!
Did you forget about Dino?!
I'm at my limit!
DINO!!!!!
Survival Instinct!
Molting!
I am....
the King of Dinosaurs
Dino!
Molting?!
My kin...
lay waste to everything!
Nooo!
Kanna-san!
Ah!
Dino!
You were having a nightmare,
are you okay?
We're back...
Was it a dream?
Let me introduce our new club member!
It's Matajiro-sensei!
Nice to meet you!